Michael Takeuchi

Phoenix, AZ 85016 | 310-256-8272 | Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Website

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Web developer with knowledge in Ruby and Javascript, passionate about creating web applications. Understanding Object-Oriented Programming and RESTful standards, with experience in prioritizing tasks utilizing test-driven development. Bringing a background in sales, I have strong skills in collaborating and effectively communicating with a team, as well as handling customer needs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Wine Journal - Github | Website

Wine journal to document wine profiles.

- Designed Rails API backend with React frontend and used Material UI to build components and styling.
- Stored data on postgresql to record wine details with associations to varietals and origins.

Meals Lookup- Github | Website

Meals site to search a variety of meals by name, category, or first letter.

- Constructed a React app with react-router to display meals as a list and a selected meal's detailed page.
- Utilized MealsDB API, to retrieve meals data, based on a user's search.

Social Golf - Github | Website

Add and review golf courses that you and others have played at.

- Developed Javascript web app with CRUD functionality, and used Bootstrap framework for styling.
- Utilized mapbox to display a map and marker for golf courses, and cloudinary to store images.

EXPERIENCE

Southern Glazer's Wine & Spirits

Torrance, CA

Chain Sales Merchandiser

05/2016 - 03/2020

- Built displays in 50% of accounts that helped buyers reduce inventory by 20% and increased sales over 30% YoY, during Q4 in 2018.
- Helped 5 new accounts organize wine and liquor department plans during grand openings.

Endeavor Society

Santa Monica, CA

Finance Intern

10/2015 - 12/2015

- Created spreadsheets to record projected profits for planned events the organization would host.
- Contributed in designing an employee performance tracker, to provide insight in employees effectiveness and efficiency at work .

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/2020 - 11/2020

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA 06/2015

Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Economics